Gloria Mutunga

Phone: +254 725 251 523 Email: gloria.mutunga@gmail.com

Summary

Oracle Certified Expert (OCE) database administrator with 7+ years' experience deploying and supporting database solutions. I am proficient in an assortment of technologies, including Oracle database (11g,12c and 19c), Real application clusters, Active Data guard, Audit Vault and Database Firewall, Enterprise manager cloud control, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Linux and Unix.

Core skills include:

- Database deployment and Administration
- Performance Tuning
- Data Security, Backup & Recovery
- Standby/Failover Administration
- Python, Flask, Jquery/Javascript, HTML5/CSS3
- Oracle RAC & ASM Configuration
- Monitoring solutions
- Automation of administrative tasks
- Linux and Unix operating systems
- PostgresSQl and MySQl databases

Educational Background

2017-Present	Master of Science (Information Technology Management), University of Nairobi Expected graduation August 2020
2008–2012	Bsc. Computer Science, University of Nairobi Graduated with First Class honors
2003–2003	Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education, Precious Blood Secondary School Graduated with mean grade A

Relevant Experience

Oct 2019-Present Nairobi, Kenya

Oracle Database Consultant, Swiftlake Technologies

- Deployment and support of Oracle database solutions
- Advise customers on Oracle Licensing and appropriate products for business continuity
- Assist customers with designing and implementing database backups strategies
- Performance tuning and capacity planing

Aug 2016-Oct 2019 Nairobi, Kenya

Enterprise Applications Manager (databases), Atlancis Technologies ltd

• Lead deployment and support of databases, middleware and ERP projects for diverse clients.

- As the lead database administrator, I was responsible for the deployment of the major database projects.
- Responsible for ensuring compliance to customers service level agreements (SLAs) requirements for databases and related solutions.
- Proactively monitored clients' databases to ensure smooth operations and minimal down time

Key Projects:

- Installation and Configuration of Oracle Real application clusters, Oracle database 12c, Active
 Dataguard and Oracle Enterprise manager 13c cloud control at Kenya Power Limited
- Upgrade, migration and consolidation of databases across different platforms at Kenya Power Limited
- Deployment and support of Oracle database and Real Application Clusters Unaitas Bank
- Implementation and support of Oracle Audit Vault and Database firewall at Chase Bank
- Implementation and support of Oracle Audit Vault and Database firewall at Alliance for a Green Revolution in Africa.
- Implementation and support of Oracle databases –Guaranty Trust Bank Kenya

April 2015-August 2016

Nairobi, Kenya

Senior database administrtaor, Atlancis Technologies ltd

- Responsible for deployment of database solutions for customers in Kenya, Uganda, Rwanda and Malawi
- Coordinated support activities for clients as per service level agreements (SLAs)
- Supported the sales team by performing product demos and presentations to potential customers Projects:
 - Installation and Configuration of Oracle Real application clusters, Oracle database 12c, Active
 Dataguard and Oracle Enterprise manager 13c cloud control at Kenya Power Limited
 - Upgrade, migration and consolidation of databases across different platforms at Kenya Power Limited
 - Deployment and support of Oracle database and Real Application Clusters Unaitas Bank
 - Implementation and support of Oracle Audit Vault and Database firewall at Chase Bank
 - Deployment of Oracle Real Application Clusters, Active Dataguard and Oracle Enterprise
 Manager 12c cloud Control at Gulf African Bank.
 - Implemented Active Dataguard at Guaranty Trust Bank: Kenya, Rwanda and Uganda
 - Upgrade of Oracle databases and deployment of Dataguard at Nico General Insurance-Malawi

Mar 2013-April 2015 Nairobi, Kenya

Oracle Database Support Engineer, The Copy Cat Group

- Deployed database solutions to various clients in the private and public sector.
- Performed database monitoring and troubleshooting
- Automated database backups as per clients' requirements
- Trained clients after projects' implementation
- Provided Tier 2 and Tier 3 support to existing clients

Sep 2012-Mar 2013 Nairobi, Kenya

Software engineer, Digimatt360

Developed web applications for various clients and provided post implementation support.

Professional Qualifications

- Oracle Grid infrastructure and Real Application Clusters 12c Certified Expert (OCE
- Oracle Grid infrastructure and Real Application Clusters 11g Certified Expert (OCE)
- Oracle Certified Professional Database Administrator 12c (OCP)
- Oracle Certified Professional Database Administrator 11g (OCP)
- Oracle Business intelligence Certified implementation specialist 12c
- Oracle Weblogic 12c Implementation specialist
- IBM WebSphere Application Server Network deployment
- Oracle enterprise manager cloud control 12c certified administrator
- Oracle Exadata certified support specialist